MAY 2000 SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
2000년 5월 서울경찰청
I'm a statistics analyst who got transferred here.
저는 통계 분석가로 여기로 전근했습니다.
Where is the office for the Behavioral Analysis Team?
행동분석팀 사무실은 어디에 있나요 ?
The Behavioral Analysis Team?
행동분석팀?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
Have you heard of it?
들어본 적 있나요?
No, I've never heard of it.
아니요, 들어본 적이 없습니다.
We had a team like that?
우리도 그런 팀이 있었나요?
Same here.
여기서도 마찬가지입니다.
Is it new?
새로운 것인가요?
I haven't heard of it.
들어본 적이 없습니다.
We don't know where it is.
우리는 그것이 어디에 있는지 모릅니다.
The Behavioral Analysis Team? What do people do there?
행동분석팀? 사람들은 거기서 무엇을 하나요?
BEHAVIORAL ANALYSIS TEAM
행동분석팀
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
승인 된 인원 만 가능
-Hello. -Hi.
-안녕하세요. -안녕.
-Who are you?
-누구세요?
I'm a statistics analyst who was transferred here.
저는 여기로 전근된 통계분석가입니다 .
My name is Jung Woo-ju.
제 이름은 정우주입니다.
-Nice to meet you. -Same here.
-만나서 반가워요. -여기도 마찬가지예요.
-See you later. -Okay.
-나중에 봐요. -좋아요.
Okay.
좋아요.
CHANGEUI PRECINCT
창의지구
As you can see, we filed your child missing.
보시다시피 귀하의 자녀를 실종 신고했습니다.
If we hear anything about Soo-hyun, we will call you right away.
수현씨 소식이 들리면 바로 전화드리겠습니다.
Staying here won't help.
여기에 머무르는 것은 도움이 되지 않습니다.
So you should go back home.
그러니 집으로 돌아가야 합니다.
But it's been over a week already.
그런데 벌써 일주일이 넘었어요.
You don't think…
당신은 생각하지 않는다…
-something bad happened to… -Stop.
-뭔가 안 좋은 일이 있었는데... -그만해요.
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마세요.
A lot of children her age get lost
그 또래의 많은 아이들이 길을 잃습니다.
and we get calls from the protection center.
그리고 보호센터에서 전화가 옵니다 .
So don't worry too much. Let's give it some time.
그러니 너무 걱정하지 마세요. 시간을 좀 봅시다.
-Thank you. -Sure.
-감사합니다. -확신하는.
-Bye.
-안녕.
-We'll wait for your call. -Sure. Bye.
-당신의 전화를 기다리겠습니다. -확신하는. 안녕.
Dad.
아빠.
When is Soo-hyun coming back?
수현이는 언제 돌아오나요?
She'll come home soon.
그녀는 곧 집에 올 것이다.
Gosh. We're visiting a prison on a gorgeous day like today?
이런. 오늘처럼 날씨가 좋은 날 감옥을 방문한다고요 ?
Should we play hooky today?
오늘은 푹 빠져볼까?
Today is our first meeting.
오늘은 우리의 첫 번째 회의입니다.
I was just joking.
그냥 농담 한거야.
Don't be so serious.
너무 심각하게 생각하지 마세요.
Goodness. This is nice.
선량. 이거 좋다.
ESTABLISH LAW AND ORDER
법과 질서를 확립하라
Inmate 3429. You have visitors.
수감자 3429. 방문객이 있습니다.
CRIME SCENE PHOTOS
범죄 현장 사진
Hey, how come we only have
이봐, 왜 우리에겐 이것 밖에 없지?
outdated items in the inventory?
인벤토리에 오래된 아이템이 있나요?
Does this thing even work? Does it?
이게 작동하는 걸까요? 그렇습니까?
Goodness. It works.
선량. 효과가있다.
First of all, don't be nervous.
우선, 긴장하지 마세요.
We'll call you once we're done.
완료되면 전화드리겠습니다.
Take a seat.
앉아 요.
JANG DEUK-HO DISMEMBERED HIS MISTRESS IN BUGYEONG-DONG
장득호는 부경동에서 여주인의 시신을 토막냈다
I'm Song Ha-young,
저는 송하영이에요.
a profiler of the Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀 의 프로파일러 .
I'm the captain of the team.
나는 팀의 주장이다.
I'm Kook Young-soo.
저는 국영수입니다.
Is this a joke?
지금 농담하는 거지?
We are police officers
우리는 경찰관이다
who study the psychology of criminals.
범죄자의 심리학을 연구하는 사람.
You're just cops.
당신은 단지 경찰입니다.
Why are you giving me a complicated title?
왜 복잡한 제목을 주시나요?
We came here today
우리 오늘 여기 왔어
because we want to know why you committed such a crime six years ago.
왜냐하면 우리는 당신이 6년 전에 왜 그런 범죄를 저질렀는지 알고 싶기 때문입니다 .
You barge in here
당신은 여기에 바지선
because you want to know what happened six years ago?
6년 전에 무슨 일이 일어났는지 알고 싶어서요 ?
As I told you,
내가 너에게 말한대로,
it's to study the psychology of criminals.
범죄자의 심리를 연구하는 거죠.
What's in it for me?
나에게 무엇이 들어있나요?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
How about some cigarettes?
담배 좀 어때요?
Let me say this again.
다시 한 번 말하겠습니다.
-You will not get any benefits. -Why would I tell you then?
- 어떠한 혜택도 받으실 수 없습니다. -그럼 내가 왜 말하겠어요?
About what happened six years ago,
6년 전 일어난 일에 대해,
if I'm not getting anything in return?
내가 대가를 받지 못한다면?
We're figuring out the wrong answers for data.
우리는 데이터에 대한 잘못된 답을 찾아내고 있습니다 .
Haven't heard "wrong answers" in a while.
한동안 "잘못된 답변"을 듣지 못했습니다.
I used to make my students write notes for wrong answers.
나는 학생들에게 오답에 대해 메모를 쓰게 하곤 했습니다 .
When you were a teacher at Bugyeong Primary School?
부경초등학교 교사였을 때요 ?
You know everything. What else do you want to know?
넌 다 아는군. 또 무엇을 알고 싶나요?
We have your case file.
귀하의 사건 파일이 있습니다.
But we're interested in your thoughts.
하지만 우리는 당신의 생각에 관심이 있습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
We can't find them in your case file.
귀하의 사건 파일에서는 해당 내용을 찾을 수 없습니다.
I thought it would be fun to meet cops.
경찰을 만나면 재미있을 거라고 생각했어요.
But it's no fun.
하지만 재미가 없습니다.
Hey! We're done here.
여기요! 이제 끝났습니다.
Six years ago, you cut your lover,
6년 전, 당신은 연인과 헤어졌고,
Lee Geum-ju, into 23 pieces.
이금주, 23조각으로.
You don't know everything, I guess.
내 생각엔 당신이 모든 것을 알지 못하는 것 같아요.
It's 24 pieces.
24개 입니다.
It says 23 in the case file.
사건 파일에는 23이라고 나와 있습니다.
Arms and legs…
팔과 다리들…
Cut them off and divide them into two. How many do you have?
잘라서 두 개로 나눕니다. 당신은 몇 개를 갖고 있나요?
There are nine.
9개가 있습니다.
You can't do the math.
당신은 수학을 할 수 없습니다.
Then you cut her neck, pulled out her eyeballs,
그런 다음 그녀의 목을 자르고 눈알을 뽑았습니다.
cut her nose, ears, lips into two,
코, 귀, 입술을 둘로 자르고,
breasts, thumbs, and big toes.
가슴, 엄지손가락, 엄지발가락.
That adds up to 23.
합하면 23이 됩니다.
You forgot one.
당신은 하나를 잊어 버렸습니다.
Did you cut off her tongue?
그 사람 혀를 잘랐나요?
She talked too much.
그녀는 말을 너무 많이 했어요.
You see, I…
알다시피, 나는…
She was dead, for sure.
그녀는 확실히 죽었습니다.
But she wouldn't stop talking.
하지만 그녀는 말을 멈추지 않았습니다.
That witch kept on talking,
그 마녀는 계속 말을 했고,
so I bit it off. Like this.
그래서 나는 그것을 깨물었다. 이와 같이.
Then it was better.
그러면 더 좋아졌습니다.
Do you have gum? Can I have a piece?
껌 있어요? 한 조각 주실 수 있나요?
You chewed it off?
씹어 먹었어요?
Her tongue?
그녀의 혀?
Why?
왜?
We should wrap this up here today.
오늘은 여기서 마무리해야겠습니다.
I need to use the bathroom.
욕실을 써야 할 것 같은데요.
We'll wait. It hasn't been ten minutes yet.
기다리겠습니다. 아직 10분도 안 됐어요.
You'll come back since you want me.
당신은 나를 원하기 때문에 돌아올 것입니다.
Let me make the call
전화 좀 할게요
so I'd want to talk to you.
그래서 당신과 이야기하고 싶습니다.
Don't you prefer this over being locked up in your cell?
감방에 갇히는 것보다 이게 더 마음에 들지 않나요 ?
Officer!
장교!
ESTABLISH LAW AND ORDER
법과 질서를 확립하라
CHEONGSONG PRISON
청송교도소
-Can you unlock the door? -Oh, sorry.
-문을 열 수 있나요? -아, 미안해요.
Oh, boy.
오 소년.
Do you go to church?
교회 다녀요?
I'm Catholic, but I haven't been to church for a long time.
저는 가톨릭 신자이지만 오랫동안 교회에 가본 적이 없습니다 .
Ever since I got this job,
이 직업을 얻은 이후로,
I've been struggling to believe in god.
나는 신을 믿으려고 애썼다.
It's better than believing in humans.
사람을 믿는 것보다 낫습니다.
If doomsday were to come,
만약 최후의 날이 온다면,
scumbags like Jang Deuk-ho would be wiped out, right?
장득호같은 쓰레기는 다 망하겠지?
SAUNA
찜질방
I totally forgot about the newbie.
나는 초보자에 대해 완전히 잊어 버렸습니다.
Darn it.
젠장.
Where's this sound coming from?
이 소리는 어디서 나오는 걸까요?
Behavioral Analysis Team. Jung Woo-ju speaking.
행동분석팀. 말하는 정우주.
My gosh, you're still there?
맙소사, 아직 거기 있나요?
Who is this?
누구세요?
This is Captain Kook Young-soo.
국영수 선장입니다.
Yes, Captain.
네, 캡틴.
You should've just gone home.
넌 그냥 집에 갔어야 했는데.
-You said you wanted to meet with me. -Gosh, I'm sorry.
-나랑 만나고 싶다고 했잖아. -맙소사, 미안해요.
I was occupied all day, so I forgot.
하루종일 바빠서 잊어버렸어요.
Just go home. We'll talk tomorrow.
그냥 집에 가세요. 내일 얘기하자.
Okay. I'm sorry.
좋아요. 죄송합니다.
I totally forgot to look after the newbie.
나는 새내기를 돌보는 것을 완전히 잊어버렸다.
Hey, wait up.
잠깐만요.
Goodness. You're always so predictable.
선량. 당신은 항상 예측 가능해요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I'm starving. Let's go eat something.
배고파 죽겠 어. 뭔가 먹으러 가자.
I don't feel like eating. I'll just head home.
먹고 싶지 않아요. 그냥 집으로 갈게요.
You should still eat something.
그래도 뭔가를 먹어야 해요.
Come on. I don't want to eat alone at home.
어서 해봐요. 집에서 혼자 밥 먹고 싶지 않아요.
Your family must be waiting for you.
당신의 가족이 당신을 기다리고 있을 겁니다.
You didn't know? I've been living alone since last year.
몰랐어요? 작년부터 혼자 살고 있어요.
No, it's not what you're thinking.
아니요, 당신이 생각하는 그런 것이 아닙니다.
My wife and kids are abroad now.
아내와 아이들은 지금 해외에 있습니다.
-They're abroad? -Yes.
-해외에 있어요? -예.
I forgot the name,
이름을 잊어버렸어요,
but a school in Singapore offered a scholarship,
그런데 싱가포르의 한 학교에서 장학금을 제안했어요.
so I sent them there.
그래서 나는 그들을 그곳으로 보냈습니다.
Your kids must be smart.
당신의 아이들은 똑똑해야합니다.
Yes. They take after my wife.
예. 그들은 내 아내를 닮아갑니다.
Oh, boy.
오 소년.
Anyway, this job is always so unstable, you know.
그나저나 이 일은 늘 불안정하잖아요.
It seemed like a good chance, so I agreed.
좋은 기회인 것 같아서 동의했습니다.
But living alone is awful.
그러나 혼자 사는 것은 끔찍합니다.
Everyone says they're jealous, but they have no idea.
모두들 질투난다고 말하지만 전혀 모릅니다.
The freedom was nice for a month, but that was it.
한 달 동안의 자유는 좋았지 만 그게 전부였습니다.
Which restaurant?
어느 레스토랑?
Just any restaurant on the way.
가는 길에 아무 레스토랑이나.
I should grab a bite before the restaurants close.
식당이 문을 닫기 전에 한 입 먹어봐야겠어요 .
MAY 2000, CHANGEUI-DONG
2000년 5월 창의동
-Did something happen? -Yes.
-무슨 일 있었어? -예.
-My gosh. -What happened?
-이럴수가. -무슨 일이에요?
-What? -Is it a kid?
-무엇? - 어린아이인가요?
-It's a little kid. -My gosh.
-어린아이입니다. -이럴수가.
-This is insane. -Gosh.
- 이건 미친 짓이야. -맙소사.
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
-Go on in. -Yes, sir.
- 들어가세요. - 예, 선생님.
-Hello, sir.
-안녕하세요 선생님.
Where is Captain Yoon?
윤 선장은 어디에 있습니까?
She's on the phone with the chief of Forensics.
그녀는 법의학 국장과 통화 중입니다 .
She'll be here.
그녀는 여기 있을 것이다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
CHANGEUI-DONG MUTILATION MURDER CASE
창의동 훼손살인사건
INSPECTOR YOON TAE-GU CAPTAIN OF TEAM 2, SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1
윤태구 경위 특수범죄수사대 1 2팀대장
I'll start the briefing.
브리핑을 시작하겠습니다.
TIME OF INCIDENT LOCATION OF THE BODY FOUND
사고 시간 발견된 시체의 위치
At around 1:20 p.m. today,
오늘 오후 1시 20분쯤,
parts of the victim's body were found
피해자의 신체 일부가 발견됐다.
by Lee Chun-young, a 72-year-old junk collector,
72세 쓰레기 수집가 이춘영 씨의
in the alleyway at 94 Changeui-dong.
창의동 94번지 골목
The news spread quickly because of
때문에 소식은 빠르게 퍼졌다.
a reporter who lives in the area,
그 지역에 사는 기자,
and it became nationwide news.
그리고 그것은 전국적인 뉴스가 되었습니다.
The case was transferred to the Special Crime Squad at 5:00 p.m.
사건은 오후 5시께 특수범죄수사대로 이첩됐다.
The rest of the body?
나머지 신체?
So far, we've only found the limbs cut up into eight pieces.
지금까지 우리는 팔다리가 여덟 조각으로 잘려진 것을 발견했습니다.
They were placed in three plastic bags.
비닐봉지 3개에 담겨 있었습니다.
We are thoroughly searching the area to find the rest of the body.
우리는 나머지 시신을 찾기 위해 해당 지역을 철저히 수색하고 있습니다 .
Have we identified the victim?
피해자의 신원은 확인됐나요?
A five-year-old girl, Lee Soo-hyun, was reported missing
5세 여아 이수현 실종 신고
in Changeui-dong on the 20th, so we're looking into it now.
20일 창의동에서 발견돼 현재 조사 중이다.
Goodness.
선량.
-This is crazy. -Search thoroughly!
- 이건 미친 짓이야. -철저히 검색해보세요!
There is so much junk here. Darn it.
여기에는 쓰레기가 너무 많습니다. 젠장.
Detective!
형사!
Soo-hyun… Did you find Soo-hyun?
수현… 수현을 찾았나요?
She was found dead in Changeui-dong.
창의동에서 숨진 채 발견됐다.
Are you sure it's Soo-hyun?
수현씨 맞나요?
No, that can't be.
아니, 그럴 리가 없어.
-No… -No way.
-안돼… -안돼.
-My gosh. -Are you all right, ma'am?
-이럴수가. -괜찮으세요, 부인?
No! That can't be!
아니요! 그럴 리가 없어!
It's not Soo-hyun. This can't be true!
수현이 아니에요. 이것은 사실일 수 없습니다!
Oh, dear…
이런…
Early this morning, the police found a head and a torso,
오늘 아침 일찍 경찰은 머리와 몸통을 발견했습니다.
which are suspected to belong to the child
아동의 것으로 의심되는
found dead in Changeui-dong.
창의동에서 숨진 채 발견
They are working on identifying the victim.
피해자를 식별하기 위해 노력하고 있습니다 .
Yesterday afternoon, the arms and legs were found cut up into pieces.
어제 오후, 팔과 다리가 잘린 채로 발견되었습니다.
The police have requested a DNA test from the National Forensic Service.
경찰은 국과수에 DNA 검사를 요청했습니다.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY PRESS ROOM
서울경찰청 기자실
Can you ask them for a briefing on the case?
사건에 대한 브리핑을 요청해 주실 수 있나요 ?
Give us some time, will you?
시간 좀 줘, 응?
You're here.
너 여기 있네.
Hey, I know that you're new here, but you're still a journalist.
안녕하세요, 당신이 여기에 처음 왔다는 것을 압니다. 하지만 당신은 여전히 ​​저널리스트입니다.
You can't stay relaxed at your desk all day.
하루 종일 책상에 앉아 편안하게 있을 수는 없습니다 .
I'm not relaxed right now.
나는 지금 편안하지 않습니다.
Anyone would say you're relaxed right now.
지금은 편안하다고 누구라도 말할 것입니다.
How much longer will you sit back and watch?
언제까지 앉아서 지켜볼 것인가?
We have to attend the press forum later today.
우리는 오늘 늦게 언론 포럼에 참석해야 합니다 .
That's later.
그건 나중에요.
Pick up your camera and go.
카메라를 들고 가세요.
Go where?
어디로 가야?
Anywhere where you can score a big scoop.
큰 특종을 얻을 수 있는 곳이면 어디든 가능합니다.
Reporter Choi, run.
최 기자, 달려가세요.
-Yes, sir. -Run!
-알겠습니다. -달리다!
All right, it's time to step up your game!
이제 게임을 강화할 시간입니다!
I'll see you later.
나중에 뵙겠습니다.
CHANGEUI-DONG DISMEMBERED BODY MORE BODY PARTS FOUND IN BUMYEONG-DONG
창의동 사지 절단된 시신, 부명동에서 더 많은 신체 부위 발견
What is this world turning into?
이 세상은 무엇으로 변하고 있습니까?
These scumbags…
이 쓰레기들…
-Hello, sir. -Hello.
-안녕하세요 선생님. -안녕하세요.
That's my desk.
그게 내 책상이야.
I'm sorry, sir. I don't have anywhere to sit.
죄송합니다. 나는 앉을 곳이 없어요.
-You saw the news, right? -Yes.
-뉴스 보셨죠? -예.
-Hello, sir. -Right.
-안녕하세요 선생님. -오른쪽.
What was your name again?
이름이 뭐였지?
Jung Woo-ju, sir.
정우주 선생님.
I've been assigned to the team as a statistics analyst.
저는 팀에 통계 분석가로 배정되었습니다 .
Nice to meet you. I'm Captain Kook Young-soo.
만나서 반가워요. 저는 국영수 선장입니다.
This is Inspector Song Ha-young, our profiler.
프로파일러 송하영 경위입니다 .
The victim is a five-year-old girl.
피해자는 5세 여자아이다.
-Five years old? -Yes.
-다섯 살? -예.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
I don't have a desk.
책상이 없어요.
A desk…
책상…
-Just let him use this one. -What about this?
-그가 이것을 사용하게 해주세요. -이건 어때요?
Gil-pyo, you need to let our team take part in this case.
길표 씨는 이 사건에 우리 팀이 참여 하게 해주세요 .
Where are you? Are you in here?
어디세요? 당신은 여기에 있습니까?
All right. I'll talk to the team.
괜찮은. 내가 팀에 얘기해 볼게.
Gil-pyo, we met Jang Deuk…
길표, 장득과 함께…
We interviewed a mutilation murderer.
우리는 절단 살인자를 인터뷰했습니다.
You punk.
이 새끼야.
Hey, do you think this is child's play?
야, 이게 어린이 장난이라고 생각하니?
I already have a lot going on.
나는 이미 많은 일을 겪고 있습니다.
You think I'm joking?
내가 농담하는 것 같나요?
I said I'll talk to them!
내가 그들과 얘기하겠다고 했어요!
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Where should I put this?
이걸 어디에 넣어야 하나요?
Wherever you want to sit.
당신이 앉고 싶은 곳에.
Wherever I want to…
내가 원하는 곳은 어디든…
Okay.
좋아요.
Where I want to sit.
내가 앉고 싶은 자리.
FOUND EIGHT BODY PIECES OF THE VICTIM, A YOUNG CHILD
피해자, 어린 아이 의 시신 8구 발견
-Is your blood type B? -Yes.
- 혈액형은 B형인가요? -예.
-Was that an insult? -Sorry?
- 모욕이었나요? -죄송합니다?
No, not at all. My blood type is B too.
아니요, 전혀 그렇지 않습니다. 제 혈액형도 B형이에요.
I see.
알겠어요.
THE MURDER ENRAGES THE PUBLIC, POLICE PRESSES CITIZEN'S REPORT
살인은 대중을 분노하게 만들고 경찰은 시민의 보고서를 발표합니다
Why did you apply for the Behavioral Analysis Team?
행동분석팀 에 지원한 이유는 무엇인가요 ?
It looked cool.
멋져 보였습니다.
Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀.
It already sounds cool.
벌써 멋지네요.
Statistic analyst
통계 분석가
of the Behavioral Analysis Team of Detective Division,
수사과 행동분석팀 ,
Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
서울지방경찰청.
Cool.
시원한.
THE CULPRIT HIDES THE BODY IN A PLASTIC BAG
범인은 시신을 비닐봉지에 숨겨
POLICE PRESUME THE CULPRIT IS A MENTAL PATIENT
경찰은 범인이 정신질환자인 것으로 추정하고 있다.
Do you know the story of the blind man and a lantern?
맹인과 등불 이야기를 아시나요 ?
-Sorry? -Someone asked a blind man
-죄송합니다? -누군가가 시각 장애인에게 물었습니다.
who was walking down a dark road with a lantern in his hand.
등불을 손에 들고 어두운 길을 걷고 있던 사람 .
"You can't see anyway. Why do you carry that around?"
"아무래도 볼 수 없잖아. 그걸 왜 가지고 다니냐?"
Why do you think so?
왜 그렇게 생각하시나요?
Why was he carrying that?
왜 그 사람이 그걸 들고 있었나요?
He wanted others to see clearly
그는 다른 사람들이 명확하게 볼 수 있기를 원했습니다
and not fall down while walking.
그리고 걸을 때 넘어지지 마세요.
He lit up the road for others, not for himself.
그는 자신을 위해서가 아니라 다른 사람들을 위해 길을 밝혔습니다 .
It's tough to last unless you have this attitude
이런 태도가 아니면 버티기 힘들다
when you start a career in coming across criminals.
범죄자를 만나는 직업을 시작할 때 .
I see.
알겠어요.
You stashed us in storage as if we got demoted.
당신은 우리가 강등된 것처럼 우리를 창고에 숨겨두었습니다 .
And we only have two men.
그리고 우리에겐 남자가 둘뿐이에요.
No, we only now have one more.
아니요, 이제 하나만 더 남았습니다.
We're not even a real team.
우리는 진짜 팀도 아닙니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
Special Crime Squad is very busy.
특수수사대는 매우 바쁘다.
We don't even have time to smoke.
우리는 담배를 피울 시간조차 없습니다.
You know what it's like. Cut it out.
당신은 그것이 어떤 것인지 알고 있습니다. 잘라내 다.
We aren't some hecklers.
우리는 야유꾼이 아닙니다.
We're trying to help out with the investigation.
우리는 조사를 돕기 위해 노력하고 있습니다 .
I know, but it's still too early.
알아요. 하지만 아직은 너무 이르죠.
You know people don't know
사람들이 모르는 걸 알잖아
what exactly the Behavioral Analysis Team does.
행동분석팀이 정확히 어떤 일을 하는지.
Of course.
물론.
You stashed us in some shabby storage.
당신은 우리를 허름한 창고에 숨겨두었습니다.
We didn't have the budget and the staff,
예산도 없고 인력도 없었는데
but you insisted on making the team in haste.
그런데 당신은 서둘러 팀을 구성하라고 고집했어요.
That was the only room available.
그 방이 유일하게 이용 가능한 방이었어요.
We report to the Detective Division.
우리는 탐정부에보고합니다.
I'm telling Superintendent Baek.
백 감독관에게 말해요.
Wait. Stop right there.
기다리다. 바로 거기서 멈춰라.
Report or whatever, you aren't the chief anymore.
신고든 뭐든, 당신은 더 이상 우두머리가 아닙니다.
You have to go through me.
당신은 나를 통과해야합니다.
I know we're close,
난 우리가 가까이 있다는 걸 알아요
but let's not destroy the reporting lines.
하지만 보고 라인을 파괴하지는 말자.
-What do you expect, then? -One second.
-그럼 어떻게 예상하시나요? -일초.
My phone smells weird.
휴대폰에서 이상한 냄새가 나요.
-Why? -I think something is served.
-왜? - 뭔가 제공되는 것 같아요.
You got served.
당신은 봉사를 받았습니다.
You wouldn't listen to me when I tried to stop you!
내가 당신을 막으려고 했을 때 당신은 내 말을 듣지 않았습니다 !
Hey, others are dying to climb up the ladder.
안녕하세요, 다른 사람들은 사다리를 오르고 싶어 죽고 있습니다 .
No one told you to get demoted.
아무도 당신에게 강등하라고 말하지 않았습니다.
It's because this job is that important.
이 직업이 그만큼 중요하기 때문이죠.
Whatever.
무엇이든.
I'm going directly to the captain.
선장에게 직접 가겠습니다.
Hey, wait. Get back here.
어이 기다려. 여기로 돌아오세요.
Stay conscious of the men above and continue to interview inmates.
위의 사람들을 의식 하고 계속해서 수감자들과 인터뷰하십시오.
Then at least share the daily report of the investigation with us.
그런 다음 적어도 일일 조사 보고서를 우리와 공유하십시오.
-How can I share that as I like? -What can you share, then?
-어떻게 하면 내 마음대로 공유할 수 있나요? -그럼 무엇을 공유할 수 있나요?
My love for you.
당신에 대한 나의 사랑.
I can always share that.
나는 항상 그것을 공유할 수 있습니다.
Good grief.
맙소사.
I'm ordering jjajangmyeon. Want some?
저는 짜장면을 주문하겠습니다. 좀 원하시나요?
No.
아니요.
The police noted there were no calls from the culprit
경찰은 범인으로부터 전화가 없었다고 확인했습니다
to demand money from the family of the victim.
피해자 가족에게 돈을 요구합니다 .
Thus, a mentally ill person.
그러니까 정신병자
-Might be the killer. -What happened?
-살인자일 수도 있습니다. -무슨 일이 일어났나요?
They won't even share the reports?
그들은 심지어 보고서를 공유하지도 않을 건가요?
I'm going to meet the captain.
선장을 만나러 갑니다.
Who's the captain of Team 2 again?
2팀 주장은 또 누구지?
Captain Yoon Tae-gu.
Captain Yoon Tae-gu.
Have you worked together?
함께 일해본 적 있나요?
For a short while, at Jungbu Station. I'll come too.
잠시 중부역에서. 나도 갈게.
Sounds great. Come with me.
좋은 것 같아요. 날 따라와.
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1
특수범죄수사대 1
Captain.
선장.
They walked out of Chief Heo's office just now.
그들은 지금 막 허과장의 사무실 에서 나갔다 .
They want us to share the case reports.
그들은 우리가 사례 보고서를 공유하기를 원합니다.
Make sure they don't freeload on our case.
그들이 우리 케이스에 프리로드되지 않도록 하세요.
I'll manage.
내가 관리할게.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
How may I help you?
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
My name is Kook Young-soo. I used to be in Forensics.
제 이름은 국영수입니다. 저는 법의학 분야에 있었습니다.
Chief Kook Young-soo of Forensics.
포렌식 국영수 과장.
You made a name for yourself, so I know who you are.
당신은 자신의 이름을 만들었 으므로 나는 당신이 누구인지 압니다.
-Thank you. -It has been a while.
-감사합니다. -오랜만이에요.
Yes.
예.
"Criminal behavioral analyst"?
"범죄 행동 분석가"?
We study the minds of criminals.
우리는 범죄자의 마음을 연구합니다.
I meet with inmates in prison, conduct interviews,
감옥에 있는 수감자들을 만나 인터뷰를 하고,
and turn that info into data.
그리고 그 정보를 데이터로 바꿔보세요.
What do you do with them?
당신은 그들에게 무엇을 합니까?
Do you run psychological tests?
심리검사를 하시나요?
It was a joke. I'm sorry if you were offended.
그것은 농담. 기분이 상하셨다면 죄송합니다.
No, it's all right.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
Not many know about our team, so I understand.
우리 팀에 대해 아는 사람이 많지 않아서 이해합니다.
Why don't we grab a seat?
자리에 앉는 게 어때요?
I'm a little busy right now.
지금은 좀 바빠요.
I see. Okay.
알겠어요. 좋아요.
We interviewed a mutilation murderer.
우리는 절단 살인자를 인터뷰했습니다.
If we find out the psychology of the criminal,
범인의 심리를 알아내면 ,
we can prevent another crime.
또 다른 범죄를 예방할 수 있습니다.
We are in a rush to resolve the case instead of preventing it.
사건 을 막기는커녕 사건 해결에 급급합니다 .
I understand. It's true, but…
이해합니다. 사실입니다만…
Instead of arresting culprits, the Behavioral Analysis Team aims
행동분석팀은 범인을 검거하는 대신
to prevent similar crimes--
유사범죄 예방을 위해
Even if all of us end up unemployed,
우리 모두가 실업자가 되어도
it would be wonderful to see a day like that.
그런 날을 볼 수 있다면 정말 좋을 것 같아요 .
Isn't that so?
그렇지 않나요?
We'd like to help with this investigation.
우리는 이 조사를 돕고 싶습니다.
The detectives in charge are more than competent.
담당 형사들은 유능합니다.
I doubt it was done by a mentally ill person.
정신병자가 한 짓인지 의심스럽네요 .
You're stepping over the line.
당신은 선을 넘어서고 있습니다.
Why are you so defensive?
왜 그렇게 방어적인 거야?
Goodness, why are you two going on with different topics?
맙소사, 왜 둘이 다른 주제로 이야기하는 거죠?
Captain Yoon, we came to see you today to help out with the investigation.
윤 대위님, 오늘은 수사에 도움을 드리고자 찾아왔습니다 .
Please don't take it the wrong way.
잘못된 방식으로 받아들이지 마십시오.
We are the ones to decide
결정하는 것은 우리다
if you will be helpful or not.
당신이 도움이 될지 말지.
As you can see, we are unbelievably busy
보시다시피 우리는 믿을 수 없을 정도로 바쁘다
because we don't even have a suspect for that darned mutilation murderer.
그 빌어먹을 살인범에 대한 용의자조차 없기 때문입니다 .
So we do not have enough resources to cooperate
그래서 우리는 협력할 자원이 충분 하지 않습니다.
with your great plan of criminal analysis or whatnot.
당신의 훌륭한 범죄 분석 계획이니 뭐니와 함께요.
In that case,
그 경우,
could you please share the investigation reports?
조사 보고서를 공유해 주실 수 있나요 ?
I know you already know the answer.
나는 당신이 이미 답을 알고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
I'm sorry to say that there's nothing I can share.
공유할 수 있는 것이 아무것도 없어서 안타깝습니다 .
We just want to help you find a suspect for the case.
우리는 단지 당신 이 사건의 용의자를 찾는 데 도움을 주고 싶을 뿐입니다 .
As you know, I'm very busy.
아시다시피 저는 매우 바빠요.
May I be excused?
실례해도 될까요?
Yes, well, in that case…
응, 그렇다면…
INSPECTOR SONG HA-YOUNG
송하영 경위
Goodness. Let's leave for now.
선량. 지금은 떠나자.
We'll find a way.
우리는 방법을 찾을 것입니다.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have come along.
죄송합니다. 난 같이 오지 말았어야 했는데.
That's irrelevant.
그것은 관련이 없습니다.
Statistics Analyst Jung Woo-ju.
통계분석가 정우주.
-Yes, sir. -I have a job for you.
-알겠습니다. -당신에게 할 일이 있어요.
Among the articles published on the Changeui-dong case,
창의동 사건을 다룬 기사 중에는
put together everything that can be used as a lead.
리드로 사용할 수 있는 모든 것을 하나로 모으세요 .
The Changeui-dong case?
창의동 사건?
The mutilated five-year-old girl.
훼손된 5세 소녀.
And instead of using that horrible name,
그리고 그 끔찍한 이름을 사용하는 대신,
we'll call it the Changeui-dong case.
창의동 사건이라고 부르겠습니다.
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다.
Hey, In-tak.
안녕, 인탁.
Hey, Young-soo. Thanks.
안녕하세요, 영수님. 감사해요.
Why did you suddenly want to meet here?
갑자기 왜 여기서 만나고 싶었어요?
Is something going on?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
You know I transferred to the Behavioral Analysis Team, right?
제가 행동분석팀 으로 전근 온 거 아시죠 ?
I heard about it, but what do you do there?
얘기는 들었는데 거기서 뭐하세요?
People were talking and saying you were demoted.
사람들은 당신이 강등됐다고 말하고 있었어요.
You won't understand even if I explain.
설명을 해도 이해 못하실 거예요.
Anyway, I wanted to ask you today
아무튼 오늘은 꼭 묻고 싶었어
if you've found any leads for the Changeui-dong case.
창의동 사건의 단서를 찾았다면요 .
Which one? The mutilated five-year-old?
어느 것? 훼손된 다섯 살짜리 아이?
-Yes. -Why are you asking me?
-예. -왜 나한테 묻는거야?
It's a complicated story.
복잡한 이야기입니다.
So you really weren't demoted?
그럼 당신은 정말로 강등되지 않았나요?
Hey, you punk.
이봐, 이 새끼야.
Am I someone who would get demoted?
나는 강등될 사람인가?
No way, you are the godfather of Forensics.
말도 안돼, 당신은 법의학의 대부입니다.
You should be promoted.
당신은 승진해야합니다.
Exactly.
정확히.
You found nothing at the scene or on her body?
현장 이나 시체에서 아무것도 발견하지 못하셨나요?
Nothing. The killer even cut up the kid's fingers.
아무것도 아님. 범인은 심지어 아이의 손가락을 잘랐습니다 .
Fingers?
손가락?
I find these cases horrifying no matter how many times I see them.
나는 이런 사례들을 몇 번을 봐도 끔찍하다고 생각한다.
I can never get used to this.
나는 이것에 결코 익숙해질 수 없다.
The killer put it in a plastic bag,
범인은 비닐봉지에 넣어뒀는데
put it in a backpack, then threw it out?
배낭에 넣었다가 버렸나요?
When the parts were found, they were frozen.
부품이 발견되었을 때 얼어붙었습니다.
I don't know how the culprit cut her, but the section looked neat.
범인이 어떻게 잘라냈는지 모르겠지만 단면이 깔끔해 보였습니다.
Let me borrow your pen.
펜을 빌려주세요.
The body was cut after it was frozen.
시체는 냉동된 후 절단되었습니다.
The cross-section is neatly cut.
단면이 깔끔하게 잘려있습니다.
Where did she go missing and when was she abducted?
그녀는 어디로 실종됐고 , 언제 납치됐나요?
The time?
시간?
By any chance,
혹시,
do you think I can look at the photos?
내가 사진을 봐도 될 것 같아?
I have them in my office.
내 사무실에 있어요.
But I can't share them.
하지만 공유할 수는 없습니다.
I'll just look at them.
나는 그것들을 살펴볼 것이다.
-Be on the lookout for me. -Okay.
-나를 조심하세요. -좋아요.
What? What are you doing?
무엇? 뭐하세요?
Hey, you know that you became the chief
야 니가 족장이 된거 알지?
because I transferred even though people were pointing fingers at me.
왜냐하면 사람들이 나에게 손가락질을 하고 있음에도 불구하고 나는 전근을 했기 때문이다 .
Yes, I do.
네 저도 그렇습니다.
Give me a second. Come on.
잠시만 기다려 주세요. 어서 해봐요.
Keep watching.
계속 시청하세요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Arms and legs…
팔과 다리…
Cut them off and divide them into two.
잘라내고 두 개로 나눕니다.
How many do you have?
몇 개 갖고 있나요?
If the culprit severed the body parts not to get caught,
범인이 잡히지 않기 위해 신체 일부를 절단했다면 ,
why would the culprit abandon the body parts nearby?
범인은 왜 근처의 신체 부위를 버렸을까요?
You're talking to me, right?
나한테 말하는 거 맞지?
I'm going out.
내가 외출 해요.
I'll be late. If Captain Kook doesn't come back, go home.
나는 늦을 것이다. 국대위가 돌아오지 않으면 집에 가세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Well,
잘,
I have a situation.
상황이 있습니다.
I see. Okay.
알겠어요. 좋아요.
You sure have a difficult job.
당신은 확실히 어려운 일을 하고 있습니다.
-How much is it? -It's 5,000 won.
-얼마입니까? - 5,000원이에요.
-Here. -Thanks.
-여기. -감사해요.
HANKUK UNIVERSITY COMMUNICATION SCIENCE FORUM
한국대학교 통신과학포럼
-Want some coffee? -Sounds good.
- 커피 마실래? - 좋은 것 같아요.
-It's over there. -Ki-ho.
-저기에있어. -기호.
Ki-ho.
기호.
It's been a while.
오랜만이야.
You too.
너도.
What a surprise.
놀랐는 걸.
Im Moo-sik of Daehan Daily is actually saying hello to me first.
실제로 대한일보 임무식님이 저에게 먼저 인사를 드리고 있습니다.
Don't be so harsh on me.
나에게 너무 가혹하게 대하지 마십시오.
I know how to show my respect.
나는 존경심을 표현하는 방법을 알고 있습니다.
No, you don't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
Well, it's nice to see you guys
음, 만나서 반가워요 여러분
working together like this.
이렇게 같이 일해요.
Fact Today. Good luck.
오늘의 사실. 행운을 빌어요.
Good luck.
행운을 빌어요.
I don't expect much. But let's do better than him.
나는 많은 것을 기대하지 않습니다. 하지만 그 사람보다 더 잘해보자.
-Yes, sir. -You're not
-알겠습니다. -넌 아니야
going to the office now. Right?
지금 사무실에 가요. 오른쪽?
Oh, I…
아, 난…
Hello?
안녕하세요?
You know that I rarely call in favors. Right?
내가 부탁을 들어주는 일이 거의 없다는 걸 당신도 알잖아요 . 오른쪽?
But I know when you start with that, you're asking a favor.
하지만 나는 당신이 그런 일을 시작하면 부탁을 하는 것임을 압니다.
What is it this time?
이번에는 무엇입니까?
If you know anything, give me some intel.
아는 게 있으면 정보 좀 주세요.
Come on. Don't ask me that. Bye.
어서 해봐요. 그런 건 묻지 마세요. 안녕.
Hey, don't hang up.
야, 전화 끊지 마.
I really need to find a lead. Can you help me out here?
정말 단서를 찾아야 해요. 여기서 나를 도와줄 수 있나요?
Gosh. Why did he just hang up on me?
이런. 그 사람은 왜 나한테 전화를 끊었나요?
See?
보다?
The desperate ones are bound to take initiative.
절박한 사람이 주도권을 잡을 수밖에 없습니다.
Do you feel like talking to me now?
지금 나랑 얘기하고 싶은 기분이 드나요?
No. Not yet.
아니, 아직.
Turn that off.
그거 끄세요.
-Happy now? -A bit.
-이제 행복해? -약간.
Don't you feel guilty?
죄책감을 느끼지 않나요?
You brutally killed a woman.
당신은 여자를 잔인하게 죽였습니다.
She was already dead anyway.
어쨌든 그녀는 이미 죽은 뒤였다.
Nothing I can do.
내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없습니다.
What's the point of holding on
붙잡고 있는 게 무슨 소용이 있겠어?
to the past and regretting it?
과거로 돌아가서 후회하나요?
It's not regretting. It's repenting.
후회하는 것이 아닙니다. 회개하는 것입니다.
Do you know something?
당신은 뭔가를 알고 있나요?
Your eyes
너의 눈
seem so familiar.
너무 친숙한 것 같아요.
There's a void
공백이 있어요
in your eyes.
눈에.
-Stop making useless comments. -I'm serious.
- 쓸데없는 댓글은 그만 두세요. -진심이에요.
Fine. I'm human, after all.
괜찮은. 결국 나는 인간입니다.
I do feel guilty from time to time.
나는 때때로 죄책감을 느낀다.
Right.
오른쪽.
You can also…
당신은 또한 수…
turn into a monster if the situation allows.
상황이 허락한다면 괴물로 변신하세요 .
-So I'm just one step away? -Yes.
- 그럼 한 발짝만 더 가면 되는 건가요? -예.
You can't consider guilt the same as murder.
죄책감을 살인과 동일하게 생각할 수는 없습니다 .
That's the difference between humans and monsters like you.
그게 바로 너 같은 괴물과 인간의 차이야 .
You think heinous crimes are the same as morality.
당신은 극악무도한 범죄가 도덕성과 동일하다고 생각합니다.
It's a horrendous thought.
끔찍한 생각입니다.
A horrendous thought?
끔찍한 생각이요?
Do you know what's really horrid?
정말 무서운 게 뭔지 아세요?
Severing the body.
시체를 절단합니다.
Then why did you do it?
그럼 왜 그랬어요?
Do you think I did it for fun?
내가 재미삼아 그런 짓을 했다고 생각하나요?
It takes a lot of time and is exhausting.
시간도 많이 걸리고 피곤합니다.
Think about it.
생각해 보세요.
Where could I go while carrying a body that big?
그토록 큰 몸을 짊어지고 어디로 갈 수 있겠는가 ?
Where could I hide her?
그녀를 어디에 숨길 수 있습니까?
Cutting her up wasn't easy.
그녀를 자르는 것은 쉽지 않았습니다.
That bitch.
그년.
So you cut her up to move her easily?
그럼 쉽게 옮기려고 잘라낸 건가요?
If that was the only reason,
그게 유일한 이유라면,
you wouldn't have removed her eyes and tongue.
당신은 그녀의 눈과 혀를 제거하지 않았을 것입니다 .
You got half right.
절반은 맞았습니다.
The other half is wrong.
나머지 절반은 틀렸습니다.
You get 50 points.
당신은 50 포인트를 얻습니다.
There's a void in your eyes.
당신의 눈에는 공허함이 있습니다.
You can also…
또한…
turn into a monster if the situation allows.
상황에 따라 괴물로 변신합니다 .
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
Where did you go?
어디로 갔나요?
-I went to meet Jang Deuk-ho. -I see.
-장득호를 만나러 갔어요. -알겠어요.
How did you get them?
어떻게 얻었나요?
From my connection.
내 연결에서.
Wait.
기다리다.
-You're missing the time and locations. -Right. I got it.
-시간과 장소가 누락되었습니다. -오른쪽. 알겠어요.
-Did you eat? -I don't have an appetite.
-밥은 먹었 니? -식욕이 없어요.
You still have to eat.
아직 먹어야 해요.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
Hey, give me that.
이봐요, 그거 주세요.
Gosh. I'm so tired.
이런. 너무 피곤해요.
-You're back. -Yes.
- 돌아왔구나. -예.
Did anyone hold grudges against her parents?
그녀의 부모에게 원한을 품은 사람이 있었나요 ?
We haven't found anyone so far. We still have to look further.
지금까지 아무도 찾지 못했습니다. 아직 더 살펴봐야 합니다.
This is the file from Forensics. I checked them by time.
포렌식스에서 나온 파일입니다. 시간별로 확인해 봤습니다.
Did you eat?
밥은 먹었 니?
-What time does the sauna open? -It should be open.
-사우나는 몇시에 오픈하나요? - 열려 있어야 합니다.
There was no ransom.
몸값은 없었습니다.
The culprit wasn't after money.
범인은 돈을 쫓는 것이 아니었습니다.
Given its brutality, we can look into those
그 잔인성을 감안할 때, 우리는
who may hold grudges against her parents.
부모에게 원한을 품을 수도 있는 사람.
But the Special Crime Squad hasn't found anyone yet.
하지만 특수수사대는 아직 누구도 찾지 못했습니다.
That's why they think the killer is mentally ill.
그래서 그들은 살인자가 정신병자라고 생각합니다.
But the body was cut too neatly for someone who's mentally unstable.
하지만 정신적으로 불안정한 사람이 보기에는 몸이 너무 깔끔하게 잘려져 있었습니다 .
The culprit cut her up by her joints.
범인은 그녀의 관절을 절단했습니다.
It means that the culprit knew the method.
범인이 수법을 알고 있었다는 뜻이다.
And each body part was put in different plastic bags.
그리고 각 신체 부위를 다른 비닐봉지에 담았습니다.
Just looking at the evidence,
증거만 봐도,
the killer must've had a job involving cutting.
살인자는 절단과 관련된 직업을 가졌음에 틀림없어요 .
What kind of job would that be?
그것은 어떤 직업이겠습니까?
This is going back to square one,
이것은 원점으로 돌아가는 것입니다.
but why was it discarded in the area?
그런데 왜 그 지역에 버려졌나요?
It's easier to find.
찾기가 더 쉽습니다.
Maybe the culprit didn't have the means to move them elsewhere.
어쩌면 범인은 그들을 다른 곳으로 옮길 수단이 없었을 수도 있습니다 .
But these were double-bagged, right?
그런데 이거 이중봉투였죠?
Yes, you're right.
네 말이 맞아.
Why double-bag them?
왜 이중 가방에 넣어야 합니까?
Maybe a butcher?
어쩌면 정육점일까요?
That's possible.
가능합니다.
A butcher.
정육점.
A BUTCHER
정육점
It's possible the culprit used a cutting machine.
범인이 절단기를 사용했을 가능성도 있습니다 .
And the way the body parts were frozen too.
그리고 신체 부위 도 얼어 붙었습니다.
But would a butcher
하지만 정육점에서는 그럴까요?
put the body parts neatly in plastic bags?
신체 부위를 비닐봉지에 가지런히 담는다?
Then maybe it's someone who works at a butcher shop.
그렇다면 정육점에서 일하는 사람일 수도 있겠네요.
Oh, that's right.
아, 그렇군요.
When you buy meat, they double-bag it in black plastic bags.
고기를 사면 검정색 비닐봉지에 이중 포장해 줍니다.
Fish too.
물고기도.
Judging by the way they were cut, I'd say a butcher,
자르는 방식으로 판단하면 정육점이라고 할 수 있겠네요.
not someone who handles fish.
생선을 다루는 사람이 아닙니다.
But don't butchers have to work during the day?
그런데 정육점 주인은 낮에도 일을 해야 하지 않나요 ?
Business owners can set their own work schedules.
사업주는 자신의 근무 일정을 설정할 수 있습니다.
Or…
또는…
someone who used to have that kind of job.
그런 직업을 가졌던 사람이에요.
Or someone who's currently unemployed.
아니면 현재 실직중인 사람.
UNEMPLOYED
한가한
And they said the killer would be someone with a mental illness.
그리고 범인은 정신질환을 앓고 있는 사람일 것이라고 말했습니다 .
-But if it's a mentally unstable person… -I'm not sure.
-하지만 정신적으로 불안정한 사람이라면… - 모르겠어요.
It's highly unlikely.
그럴 가능성은 거의 없습니다.
Because people like that can't really plan a crime like this.
그런 사람들은 이런 범죄를 계획할 수가 없거든요.
Looking at how they were cut, it has to be someone
잘린 모습을 보니 누군가임에 틀림없어요
who is skilled at cutting things.
물건을 자르는 데 능숙한 사람.
Exactly. That's how we should approach this. We should…
정확히. 이것이 우리가 이 문제에 접근해야 하는 방법입니다. 우리는…
COME AGAIN BUTCHERS
다시 오세요 ​​정육점
Excuse me. Good day, sir.
실례합니다. 좋은 하루 되세요, 선생님.
We're from the Special Crime Squad at Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
저희는 서울지방경찰청 특수수사대 소속입니다 .
We'd like to ask you a few questions regarding the recent incidents.
최근 발생한 사건과 관련하여 몇 가지 질문을 드리고자 합니다 .
Did you take some time off recently?
최근에 잠시 쉬셨나요?
Is the owner not here?
주인은 여기 없나요?
He stepped out.
그는 나갔다.
-He did? -Yes.
-그가 그랬나요? -예.
We're from the Special Crime Squad at Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
저희는 서울지방경찰청 특수수사대입니다 .
We'd like to ask you a few questions.
몇 가지 질문을 드리고 싶습니다.
On May 25,
5월 25일
did any of your employees miss work or…
직원 중에 결근한 사람이 있었나요? 아니면…
Think about it.
생각해보세요.
Where could I go while carrying a body that big?
그렇게 큰 몸을 들고 어디로 갈 수 있나요 ?
Where could I hide her?
그녀를 어디에 숨길 수 있나요?
Il-young.
일영.
Can you check the ex-cons' mental illness history?
전과자들의 정신질환 이력을 확인할 수 있나요?
SEONGDONG MENTAL HOSPITAL
성동정신병원
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1 TEAM 2
특수범죄수사대 1 팀 2
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Can you spare me a moment?
잠시만 시간을 내주실 수 있나요?
It's not like you don't know the protocol.
프로토콜을 모르는 것은 아닙니다.
Do you think we're a complete joke?
우리가 완전 농담이라고 생각하세요?
Or is it me you have no respect for?
아니면 당신이 존경하지 않는 사람은 나입니까?
What I'm saying is that the culprit is not mentally unstable.
제가 말씀드리는 것은 범인이 정신적으로 불안정한 상태가 아니라는 것입니다.
You're crossing the line again.
또 선을 넘으시네요.
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
You said you wanted to help, right?
도와주고 싶다고 했지?
-I'm trying to help you. -No.
-나는 당신을 도우려고 노력하고 있습니다. -아니요.
You're here to meddle in our work, not help us.
당신은 우리 일에 개입하려고 온 것이지, 우리를 도와주려고 온 것이 아닙니다.
We're doing just fine,
우리는 잘 지내고 있어요.
so mind your own business.
그니까 넌 너나 잘 하셔.
We've already checked all the butcher shops in the area.
우리는 이미 그 지역의 모든 정육점을 조사했습니다.
You're not the only one
당신은 유일한 사람이 아니다
who is keeping a close watch on this case.
이 사건을 면밀히 감시하고 있는 사람.
It may just be an intriguing case to you and your team,
이는 귀하와 귀하의 팀에게 흥미로운 사례일 수 있습니다 .
but my team has a duty to solve it.
하지만 우리 팀은 그 문제를 해결해야 할 의무가 있어요.
You have been interviewing some offenders in jail.
당신은 감옥에 있는 몇몇 범죄자들을 인터뷰해 왔습니다 .
Shouldn't you be interviewing more of them right now?
지금 당장 그들 중 더 많은 사람들 과 인터뷰를 해야 하지 않나요 ?
I'm sure you quit the Serious Crime Unit and accepted this new position
나는 당신이 중대범죄수사대를 그만두고 이 새로운 직위를 받아들였을 것이라고 확신합니다.
for a reason.
이런 이유로.
I don't know what it is,
나는 그것이 무엇인지 모른다.
but you should work hard to prevent future crimes.
하지만 미래의 범죄를 예방하기 위해 열심히 노력해야 합니다 .
I don't appreciate your tone.
나는 당신의 말투에 감사하지 않습니다.
We aren't doing this just because it's intriguing.
단지 흥미로워서 이 일을 하는 것이 아닙니다 .
How could you misunderstand your fellow officers like this?
어떻게 동료 장교들을 이렇게 오해할 수 있습니까 ?
Do you have a problem with my team?
우리 팀에 문제가 있나요?
Or is it me?
아니면 나인가요?
You sure have a knack
당신은 확실히 재주가 있어요
for overstepping your boundaries.
당신의 경계를 뛰어 넘었기 때문입니다.
Let me make this clear to you.
이 점을 분명히 말씀드리겠습니다.
I am the lead investigator on this case.
저는 이 사건의 수석 조사관입니다.
Do not underestimate or doubt what the Special Crime Squad can do.
특수범죄수사대가 할 수 있는 일을 과소평가하거나 의심하지 마세요 .
If you truly want to help us,
진심으로 우리를 돕고 싶다면,
do what you have to do in your own position.
자기 위치에서 해야 할 일을 하세요 .
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
28 DAYS AFTER THE INCIDENT JUNE 26, 2000
2000년 6월 26 일 사건 발생 28일 후
Hey, Lotte won yesterday.
안녕하세요, 어제 롯데가 이겼어요.
My gosh.
이럴수가.
-Oh, dear. It's so hot, isn't it? -Yes.
-이런. 너무 덥지 않나요? -예.
We can't use the AC before July.
7월 이전에는 에어컨을 사용할 수 없습니다.
Chief Heo.
허 과장.
Can you please brief us on the progress?
진행 상황을 간략하게 설명해 주실 수 있나요?
Do you have a suspect yet?
아직 용의자가 있나요?
I'll let you know when there's progress.
진전이 있으면 알려드리겠습니다.
What? All eyes are on this case now.
무엇? 지금 모든 시선이 이 사건에 쏠려 있습니다.
Are you saying there still has been no progress?
아직도 진전이 없다는 말씀이신가요 ?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
You know that we're all busting our butts now.
우리 모두 지금 엉덩이를 터뜨리고 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다 .
Well, everything is classified except for the info
음, 정보를 제외한 모든 것은 기밀입니다.
shared with the public,
대중과 공유하고,
so we cannot share anything else. Please understand.
그래서 우리는 다른 것을 공유할 수 없습니다. 이해해주세요.
Please refer to what I said when writing. I have to go.
제가 글을 쓸 때 말씀드린 부분을 참고해주세요. 나는 가야 해요.
-Come on! -Tell us what's going on!
-어서 해봐요! -무슨 일인지 알려주세요!
-Don't do this to us! -This is crazy!
-우리한테 이러지 마세요! - 이건 미친 짓이야!
Captain Yoon Tae-gu.
Captain Yoon Tae-gu.
Did you stay up all night?
밤새도록 잤어요?
What brings you here?
여기에서 당신을 제공합니다?
I transferred to the Intelligence Unit here
난 여기 정보부 로 전속됐어
two weeks ago.
2 주 전.
Really?
정말?
-You must be very busy these days. -Yes, as always.
-요즘 많이 바쁘실 텐데요. -네, 늘 그랬듯이요.
How can we chat and share information
어떻게 채팅하고 정보를 공유할 수 있나요?
with someone who doesn't smoke?
담배 안 피우는 사람이랑?
She's no fun.
그녀는 재미가 없습니다.
She's difficult to work with.
그녀는 함께 일하기가 어렵습니다.
Goodness.
선량.
They say women are chatty,
여자들은 말이 많다고 하던데,
but men are worse in my opinion.
하지만 내 생각에는 남자들이 더 나쁘다.
Is there any progress with the investigation?
수사는 진전이 있는 걸까요 ?
Well, it's not easy.
글쎄요, 쉽지 않아요.
Because you're in charge of the murder case
당신이 살인사건을 담당하고 있으니까요
in Changeui-dong,
창의동에서
losers like them are watching you with their eyes peeled.
그들 같은 패배자들은 눈을 가늘게 뜨고 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다 .
Really?
정말?
Everyone in the police force knows that you're a star player.
경찰에 있는 모든 사람들은 당신이 스타 플레이어라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
But there are still losers who complain about
하지만 여전히 불평하는 패자들이 있다.
a woman leading them.
그들을 이끄는 여자.
Losers. They're so pathetic.
패자. 정말 한심해요.
I'm so happy that you're here.
당신이 여기 있어서 정말 기뻐요.
-Take it easy. -You too.
- 진정하세요. -너도.
Come, over here!
여기로와!
A butcher.
정육점.
The victim went missing at a park during the day,
피해자는 낮에 공원에서 실종
and the body parts were found nearby.
신체 일부가 근처에서 발견되었습니다.
MISSING, LEE SOO-HYUN, AGE 5
실종 이수현, 5세
It means the culprit lives in the area.
범인이 해당 지역에 거주한다는 의미입니다.
And it has to be someone who doesn't have a set schedule.
그리고 정해진 일정이 없는 사람이어야 합니다 .
What kind of trait does the culprit have?
범인은 어떤 특성을 갖고 있나요?
Why did the killer kidnap her?
범인은 왜 그녀를 납치했나요?
Why did the killer dismember her body?
범인은 왜 시신을 절단했나요?
The body parts were found in black plastic bags.
검은색 비닐봉지에 담긴 신체 부위가 발견되었습니다 .
They were double-bagged.
그들은 이중 포장되었습니다.
Who is the culprit?
범인은 누구인가요?
I must find the culprit who killed a five-year-old kid.
다섯 살짜리 아이를 죽인 범인을 찾아야 합니다 .
MISSING, LEE SOO-HYUN, AGE 5
실종 이수현, 5세
Why was it her?
왜 그녀였나요?
-Come here! -Hey!
-이리 오세요! -여기요!
Hey, wait up!
잠깐만요!
Where is the culprit hiding?
범인은 어디에 숨어 있나요?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Captain, to the autopsy room. Hurry.
대장님, 부검실로 가세요. 서두르세요.
A fridge?
냉장고?
The body was frozen, remember?
시체가 얼어붙었잖아, 기억나?
The marks on the back seem to be from the freezer shelves.
뒷면에 있는 자국은 냉동실 선반에서 나온 것 같습니다.
Captain Kook Young-soo found it.
국영수 선장이 찾았다.
What is it about, sir?
무슨 내용인가요?
Why can't you just say it?
왜 말을 못하나요?
I know what everyone thinks about the Behavioral Analysis Team.
나는 행동분석팀에 대해 모두가 어떻게 생각하는지 알고 있습니다.
I know what's going on,
무슨 일인지 알아요
but we can give them a chance, you know?
하지만 우리는 그들에게 기회를 줄 수 있어요, 아시죠?
Kook Young-soo was the one who found the clue.
그 단서를 찾아낸 사람 은 국영수였다 .
Captain Yoon, I'm sure you know this,
윤 대위님, 알고 계시리라 믿습니다.
but it's lonely taking a path no one has ever taken before.
하지만 이전에 누구도 가보지 않은 길을 가는 것은 외로운 일입니다 .
They're probably lonely.
그들은 아마도 외로울 것입니다.
So I'd like you to help them.
그러니 당신이 그들을 도와주셨으면 합니다.
Don't get me wrong. It's not an order.
오해하지 마세요. 그것은 명령이 아닙니다.
Of course not. I'm sure she knows.
당연히 아니지. 나는 그녀가 알고 있다고 확신합니다.
Yes, sir. I should get back to work.
알겠습니다. 나는 다시 일하러 가야 해요.
-Okay, sure. -All right.
-그래, 물론이지. -괜찮은.
EVIDENCE PHOTOS
증거 사진
We'll check the junk shops in the area first.
먼저 그 지역의 고물상을 살펴보겠습니다 .
Then we'll check electronics stores in the area.
그럼 그 지역의 전자제품 매장을 확인해 보겠습니다 .
Please check thoroughly.
꼼꼼히 확인해주세요.
Will do. Good luck.
그럴 것이다. 행운을 빌어요.
-Let's go. -Yes, ma'am.
-갑시다. -네 부인.
USED FURNITURE HOME AND OFFICE ELECTRONICS
중고 가구 가정용 및 사무용 전자 제품
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Are there refrigerators with shelves that are spaced out like that?
선반이 이렇게 간격을 두고 있는 냉장고도 있나요 ?
Or did you maybe sell one?
아니면 하나 팔았나요?
Please look at the distance between the shelves.
선반 사이의 거리를 확인하세요 .
Goodness.
선량.
LEE MARKET
리마켓
Excuse me, sir.
실례합니다.
Give this person a visit.
이 사람을 방문해보세요.
-Thank you. -No problem.
-감사합니다. -괜찮아요.
-Sure.
-확신하는.
WOOSUNG JUNK
우성정크
Don't do it yourself. Let me help you.
스스로하지 마십시오. 내가 도와 줄게.
Excuse me, sir?
실례합니다?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-Hi. -Are you the owner?
-안녕. -주인이신가요?
Yes, I am. What brings you here?
네, 그렇습니다. 여기에서 당신을 제공합니다?
We're from the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
저희는 서울지방경찰청 출신입니다 .
I see. What brings you here then?
알겠어요. 그러면 당신을 여기로 데려온 이유는 무엇입니까?
We wanted to ask you a question.
우리는 당신에게 질문을 하고 싶었습니다.
This is my go-to song.
이것이 제가 즐겨 부르는 노래입니다.
Would you mind turning it off for a moment, please?
잠시만 꺼 주시겠어요 ?
Sure.
확신하는.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
The thing is, we're looking for a particular model for a fridge
문제는 우리가 특정 냉장고 모델을 찾고 있다는 것입니다.
and heard you're an expert on fridges.
당신이 냉장고 전문가라고 들었는데.
Nobody can beat me when it comes to knowledge about fridges in Korea.
한국의 냉장고 지식에 있어서는 누구도 나를 이길 수 없습니다 .
-I see. -Could you tell us what model this is?
-알겠어요. -이게 무슨 모델인지 알려주실 수 있나요?
Let me see.
어디 보자.
The model seems like a pretty old one.
모델이 꽤 오래된 것 같네요.
Hold on.
기다리다.
RESTRICTED AREA
제한 구역
Let's see here.
여기서 봅시다.
Yes, this one.
네, 이거요.
This was a model produced in 1988.
1988년에 생산된 모델입니다.
That's not a shelf, it's the interior floor of the fridge.
저건 선반이 아니고 냉장고 내부 바닥이에요.
They probably only have this at the Daesung headquarters.
아마 대성본사 에만 있는 것 같아요 .
-Thank you.
-감사합니다.
No problem.
괜찮아요.
Captain Yoon? We found the model.
윤 선장? 모델을 찾았습니다.
A report on the remaining body parts came in.
나머지 신체 부위 에 대한 보고가 들어왔습니다.
We're headed there now.
우리는 지금 거기로 향하고 있습니다.
Where is it?
어디입니까?
Detective Nam?
남 형사요?
Speed up a little more, Il-young.
좀 더 속도를 내라 일영아.
Let's catch up quickly!
빨리 따라잡자!
GYEONGSEONG-DONG, GYEONGGI PROVINCE, GWANGJU
경기도 광주 경성 동
DAWONJANG MOTEL
다원장모텔
This has never happened in my 20 years of running a motel.
제가 20년 동안 모텔을 운영하면서 이런 일은 한번도 없었습니다 .
I looked in because I heard something break
뭔가 깨지는 소리가 나서 찾아봤는데
and saw the toilet was clogged with a heavy-looking object.
그리고 변기가 무겁게 보이는 물체로 막혀 있는 것을 보았습니다.
Police.
경찰.
I thought it was a piece of meat thrown out.
버려진 고기 조각 인 줄 알았어요 .
I took it out without giving it a second thought.
고민할 틈 도 없이 꺼내봤습니다 .
You have no idea how startled I was.
내가 얼마나 놀랐는지 당신은 모를 겁니다.
My heart is still racing, young lady.
내 심장은 아직도 뛰고 있어요, 아가씨.
Yes, Director.
네, 감독님.
All the higher-ups came too.
윗분들도 다 오셨어요.
There's no doubt.
의심의 여지가 없습니다.
I'm telling you, you can trust my informant.
제 정보원을 믿으셔도 됩니다 .
I'm still the only one here.
나는 아직도 여기에 유일한 사람이다.
I'm finally getting an exclusive report.
드디어 독점 보고서를 받게 됐습니다.
You're interfering with official police duty.
당신은 공식적인 경찰 업무를 방해하고 있습니다.
-What the heck? -Stop her.
-이런 젠장? - 그만둬요.
There's no exclusive here.
여기에는 독점이 없습니다.
What nonsense are you saying?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하고 있습니까?
Let me…
내가…
-Why are you taking it? It's mine! -Ma'am.
-왜 가져가나요? 내 것이다! - 부인.
Why are you here? The higher-ups are going to get mad.
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까? 윗사람들은 화를 낼 것이다.
-You came too, Superintendent Baek. -Hey.
- 백경장님도 오셨어요. -여기요.
We found the model of the fridge.
냉장고 모델을 찾았습니다.
-What is it? -You did?
-이게 뭐죠? - 그랬어요?
-Excuse me. -Okay.
-실례합니다. -좋아요.
Is that him? The stubborn one?
그 사람인가요? 완고한 사람?
Yes. Let's talk later.
예. 나중에 이야기하자.
Hey. What about us? Young-soo!
여기요. 어떤 회사 소개? 영수!
You found the model of the fridge?
냉장고 모델을 찾았나요?
Yes, we did.
그래, 우리가 했어.
It's a Daesung fridge, manufactured in 1988.
1988년에 생산된 대성냉장고 입니다 .
This is the model.
이것이 모델입니다.
Hey, I still have a business to run.
아, 아직 할 일이 남아 있어요.
How much longer will this take, young lady?
얼마나 더 걸릴까요, 아가씨?
She's not "young lady." She's a detective.
그녀는 "젊은 아가씨"가 아닙니다. 그녀는 탐정이에요.
She's the captain in charge of this case.
그녀는 이 사건의 책임자입니다.
Please just wrap it up quickly.
빨리 마무리해주세요.
I'll have to call a shaman for cleansing.
청소를 위해 무당을 불러야겠습니다.
Is it okay if we go in now?
이제 들어가도 괜찮을까요?
Don't come in here to step on and touch things.
여기 들어와서 물건을 밟거나 만지지 마세요 .
The best way for the two of you to help is to stay right there.
두 사람이 도울 수 있는 가장 좋은 방법은 바로 그 자리에 머무르는 것입니다.
Thank you for the hard work.
노고에 감사드립니다.
Someone with experience needs to help out.
경험이 있는 사람의 도움이 필요합니다.
Young-soo.
영수.
This is strange, right?
이상하지 않나요?
He didn't come here to sleep.
그는 여기에 잠을 자러 온 것이 아닙니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
On Monday, May 29,
5월 29일 월요일
a five-year-old, Lee Soo-hyun, was dismembered
5세 이수현, 몸이 절단됐다
and parts of her body were found
그리고 그녀의 신체 일부가 발견되었습니다
in a residential area in Changeui-dong.
창의동 주택가에 있다.
Yesterday, on June 26,
어제(6월 26일)
an additional part of her body was found at a motel in Gyeongseong-dong.
경성동의 한 모텔에서 추가 시신이 발견됐다 .
Ms. Kim, the owner of the motel,
모텔 주인 김모씨.
reported it to the police
경찰에 신고했어요
when she found a part of a young child's remains
그녀가 어린 아이의 유해 일부를 발견했을 때
in the toilet of room 302 on the third floor around 3 p.m.
오후 3시쯤 3층 302호 화장실에서
According to Kim,
김씨에 따르면,
a man who looked to be in his forties,
40대 정도로 보이는 남자,
dressed in manual labor clothes,
노동복을 입고,
stayed in this room around 7 a.m. on the 25th.
25일 오전 7시쯤 이 방에 머물렀습니다 .
We will share the details
자세한 내용을 공유하겠습니다
of this ongoing investigation with the citizens.
시민과 함께 진행 중인 조사에 대해 설명합니다 .
We will do our very best in this investigation
우리는 최선을 다해 조사하겠습니다
and make sure to catch the culprit.
범인을 꼭 잡으세요.
I will end the briefing here.
여기서 브리핑을 마치겠습니다.
OUR PLEDGE
우리의 약속
We got our first-ever witness,
첫 번째 목격자를 얻었습니다.
but it didn't lead to the arrest of the culprit.
그러나 범인이 체포되지 는 않았습니다 .
The identity of the culprit
범인의 신원
has become hazier.
더 흐려졌습니다.
-There you are. -Hi.
-여기 있습니다. -안녕.
We need more support staff for the Investigation Team.
조사팀에는 지원 인력이 더 필요합니다 .
We're already maxed out. You know that too.
우리는 이미 최대치를 달성했습니다. 당신도 그것을 알고 있습니다.
It's already been a week since the additional body part was found.
추가 신체 부위가 발견된 지 벌써 일주일이 지났습니다 .
We can't delay any further.
더 이상 지체할 수 없습니다.
We don't even have enough to send out for questioning.
심문을 위해 보낼 만큼 도 부족합니다 .
Try using the Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀을 이용해 보세요.
-Chief… -You said it's urgent.
-과장님… - 긴급하다고 하셨죠.
Try asking for their help.
그들에게 도움을 요청해보세요.
Even though their method may seem unfamiliar,
그들의 방식이 낯설게 느껴질 지라도 ,
the team was still made to work for the organization too.
팀은 여전히 ​​조직을 위해 일하도록 만들어졌습니다.
They're also part of the Detective Division.
그들은 또한 탐정 부서의 일부입니다.
Also, this is off the record
게다가 이건 오프더레코드야
but the Behavioral Analysis Team may go away after this year.
하지만 행동분석팀은 올해 이후에 사라질 수도 있습니다.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
They will have to show results, in order to prove their worth.
그들은 자신의 가치를 증명하기 위해 결과를 보여야 할 것입니다 .
Those guys are just as involved as we are in this case.
그 사람들도 우리와 마찬가지로 이 사건에 연루되어 있습니다.
So try utilizing them well.
그러니 잘 활용해 보세요.
I'm certain it'll be helpful for both sides.
나는 그것이 양측 모두에게 도움이 될 것이라고 확신합니다.
The act of the culprit leaving the mutilated corpse
범인이 절단된 시체를 두고 떠나는 행위
in a residential area was to show off.
주거지역에서 뽐내기로 했습니다.
The method of the murder was so violent and advanced.
살인 방법이 너무 폭력적이고 진보적이었습니다.
It's been over a month since Soo-hyun disappeared.
수현이 사라진 지 한 달이 넘었다 .
Yet, the whereabouts of the culprit is…
그래도 범인의 행방은...
A profiler is a psychologist-like police officer,
프로파일러는 심리학자와 같은 경찰관입니다.
not a police officer-like psychologist.
경찰관 같은 심리학자는 아닙니다.
BODY PARTS FOUND
신체 부위 발견
A profiler must detect
프로파일러는 감지해야 합니다
what happened at the crime scene.
범죄 현장에서 일어난 일
There's no meaning in keeping the meeting materials within the team.
회의 자료를 팀 내에 보관하는 것은 의미가 없습니다 .
Why don't we write up a report and share it with the Investigation Team?
보고서를 작성해서 수사팀과 공유하면 어떨까요 ?
So you want to put together the reasons for our reasoning
그래서 당신은 우리의 추론에 대한 이유를 정리하고 싶습니다
and suggest it to them as a possibility?
그리고 그것을 그들에게 가능성으로 제안하시겠습니까?
Yes.
예.
There's no meaning in doing this by ourselves.
혼자서 이런 일을 하는 것은 의미가 없습니다 .
I'm not sure if she'll be convinced.
그녀가 확신할지는 잘 모르겠습니다.
We'll have to try.
우리는 노력해야 할 것입니다.
Shall we?
우리 할까요?
Profiling Report, Changeui-dong Case.
창의동 사건 프로파일링 보고서
The dismemberment of a frozen body.
얼어붙은 시체의 절단.
A mid to large-sized fridge for home was used.
가정용 중대형 냉장고를 사용했습니다.
The cross-section of the body parts.
신체 부위의 단면
The shape and the cross-section show
모양과 단면 표시
the culprit is someone who cuts frozen food.
범인은 냉동식품을 자르는 사람입니다.
All seven black plastic bags containing the parts were clean.
부품이 담긴 검정색 비닐봉지 7개는 모두 깨끗했습니다.
Two bags were used to pack the body parts.
신체 부위를 포장하는 데에는 두 개의 봉지가 사용되었습니다.
When people sell frozen products, they have a habit of wrapping them
냉동식품을 판매할 때 포장하는 습관이 있습니다
in two plastic bags.
비닐봉지 2개
The culprit likely has a history of selling frozen food
범인은 냉동식품을 판매한 이력이 있을 가능성이 높습니다
or is currently working at a butcher's shop or at a fish shop.
또는 현재 정육점이나 생선가게에서 일하고 있습니다.
The time it took for dismemberment.
해체하는데 걸린 시간
The killer took time to cut her body.
범인은 시신을 자르는 데 시간이 걸렸습니다.
If the body was cut after it was frozen,
시체를 냉동한 후 절단한 경우
the killer spent a lot of time on dismemberment.
살인자는 해체에 많은 시간을 보냈습니다 .
The culprit either lives alone
범인은 혼자 살고 있거나
or works alone.
또는 혼자 일합니다.
It would've been too dangerous to travel far with a little child.
어린 아이와 함께 멀리 여행하는 것은 너무 위험했을 것입니다 .
In conclusion,
결론적으로
the culprit is a man who lives alone,
범인은 혼자 사는 남자
but someone who likes to keep things clean.
하지만 물건을 깨끗하게 유지하는 것을 좋아하는 사람입니다 .
If you search his house, it will be neatly organized.
그의 집을 검색해 보면 깔끔하게 정리되어 있을 겁니다.
The weapon he used will also have been put away neatly.
그가 사용한 무기 도 깔끔하게 정리되어 있을 것입니다.
The crime site and his home
범죄 현장과 그의 집
may be within walking distance
도보 거리에 있을 수 있음
between the point she went missing and the victim's home.
실종된 시점 과 피해자의 집 사이
Abduction, sexual molestation, mutilation,
납치, 성추행, 절단,
and abandonment show the culprit's age is between
그리고 포기는 범인의 나이가 다음 사이임을 보여줍니다
mid-to-late-thirties to early-forties.
30대 중반부터 40대 초반까지.
His final education is presumed
최종 교육을 받은 것으로 추정됩니다
as a dropout or a middle school graduate.
자퇴자 또는 중학교 졸업자
It may be a person who has experience in selling frozen food
냉동식품 판매 경험이 있는 분일 수도 있습니다
such as a butcher, or a person who does cutting-related work,
정육점이나 절단 관련 작업을 수행하는 사람
he quits his job often and changes jobs frequently.
그는 직장을 자주 그만두고 직업을 자주 바꿉니다.
He may run a butcher shop, a raw fish restaurant,
그는 정육점, 횟집을 운영할 수도 있고
or another restaurant alone.
또는 다른 식당에서 혼자
"If someone abducted a minor for sexual purposes,
" 성적인 목적으로 미성년자를 유괴한 경우 ,
he may show characteristics that are
그는 다음과 같은 특성을 보일 수 있습니다.
common to child rapists and murderers.
아동 강간범과 살인범에게 흔한 일입니다.
He may be an introvert, be reserved,
그 사람은 내성적일 수도 있고, 내성적일 수도 있고,
and have a sexual complex."
그리고 성적 콤플렉스를 가지고 있어요."
"Premature ejaculation or impotence…"
"조루 또는 발기부전…"
How are we going to confirm that?
우리는 그것을 어떻게 확인할 것입니까?
So in summary,
요약하자면,
a man with a sexual complex
성적 콤플렉스를 갖고 있는 남자
who lives alone and likes things neat is probably the culprit. Yes?
혼자 살면서 깔끔한 걸 좋아하는 사람이 범인이겠죠. 예?
-Yes, sir. -What is this nonsense?
-알겠습니다. -이 말도 안되는 소리는 무엇입니까?
The victim was abducted at a place
피해자는 한 곳에서 납치됐다.
difficult to find for those who aren't familiar with the area.
이 지역에 익숙하지 않은 사람들은 찾기가 어렵습니다 .
It probably wasn't easy to take the victim far away
피해자를 멀리 데려가는 게 쉽지 않았을 텐데
as she cried and fought back.
그녀가 울고 반격하면서.
These two things tell us that
이 두 가지가 우리에게 말해줍니다.
the crime site and his residence are most likely within walking distance.
범죄 현장과 그의 거주지는 도보 거리 내에 있을 가능성이 높습니다.
He's most likely to reside somewhere in that area.
그 사람은 그 지역 어딘가에 거주할 가능성이 가장 높습니다 .
We already searched through the entire neighborhood.
우리는 이미 동네 전체를 검색했습니다.
We didn't find anything suspicious.
의심스러운 점은 발견되지 않았습니다.
The same goes for the butcher shop. We already investigated.
정육점도 마찬가지다. 우리는 이미 조사했습니다.
Yes, we did not just sit around.
예, 우리는 그냥 앉아만 있지 않았습니다.
Then he must've worked there in the past.
그렇다면 그 사람은 과거에 그곳에서 일했던 게 틀림없어요.
Or someone who quits
아니면 그만둔 사람이
and changes jobs frequently.
그리고 직업을 자주 바꾸죠.
If that's your theory,
그게 당신의 이론이라면,
is it possible that the culprit could be someone
범인이 누군가일 수도 있지 않을까?
who takes night shifts at a raw fish restaurant?
횟집 야간근무하는 사람 ?
It's very likely.
가능성이 매우 높습니다.
This sounds too vague.
너무 모호하게 들립니다.
Look at this in the middle.
중간에 이것을보세요.
"Abduction, sexual molestation,
"납치, 성추행,
mutilation, and abandonment show
절단 및 포기 쇼
the age is between mid-to-late-thirties to early-forties."
나이는 30대 중반에서 40대 초반이에요."
"His final education is presumed
"그의 최종 교육은 추정된다
as a dropout or a middle school graduate."
중퇴자나 중학교 졸업자로서."
"If he has a record,
"그에게 기록이 있다면,
it's most likely for theft
도난 가능성이 높음
rather than violence against a person,
사람을 향한 폭력보다는
then became punished when he was in middle and high school."
그러다 중, 고등학교 때 벌을 받았다"고 말했다.
I mean, what's your ground?
내 말은, 당신의 근거는 무엇입니까?
Our ground is the FBI's crime analysis…
우리의 근거는 FBI의 범죄분석…
Goodness, you're bringing up those Americans again.
맙소사, 당신은 그 미국인을 다시 키우고 있습니다 .
Hey, you're in Korea,
안녕하세요, 한국에 계시군요.
where the World Cup will be held in just two years.
2년 뒤에 월드컵이 열리는 곳이다 .
Also, he threw out the body parts he cut up
그리고 자신이 잘라낸 신체 부위를 버렸다.
around the neighborhood so proudly,
너무 자랑스럽게 동네를 돌아다니면서
yet you're saying he's not a smart criminal?
그런데 그 사람이 똑똑한 범죄자가 아니라는 겁니까 ?
It may look like that,
그렇게 보일 수도 있는데,
but the biggest reason he cut her body was
하지만 그가 그녀의 몸을 자른 가장 큰 이유는
so no one would find her.
그래서 아무도 그녀를 찾지 못할 것입니다.
Also, the culprit threw those out in many different areas.
또한 범인은 이를 여러 곳에 버렸다 .
It's almost like that personality type test.
성격유형검사랑 거의 비슷해요 .
"Blood type B has a feisty and selfish personality."
"B형은 까칠 하고 이기적인 성격이에요."
Isn't it something like that?
그런 것이 아닌가?
I think I trust the blood type personality theory even more.
나는 혈액형 성격 이론을 더욱 신뢰하는 것 같다.
What are you…
너 뭐야…
Here's one I find the most convincing.
제가 가장 설득력 있다고 생각하는 것이 있습니다.
"He may have a sexual complex.
“그 사람은 성적 콤플렉스를 갖고 있을 수도 있어요.
He either worked around the crime scene
그는 범죄 현장 주변에서 일했거나
or resided there."
아니면 거기 거주했거나."
"He's someone who does not have many close friends."
"그 사람은 친한 친구가 별로 없는 사람이에요."
Most sex offenders are introverted and have a sexual complex.
대부분의 성범죄자들은 ​​내성적 이고 성적 콤플렉스를 가지고 있습니다.
If he targeted a minor instead of a grown woman,
만약 성인 여성이 아닌 미성년자를 타겟으로 삼았다면 ,
it means he wanted to find an easy target who wouldn't fight him.
그것은 그가 자신과 싸우지 않을 쉬운 표적을 찾고 싶었다는 것을 의미합니다 .
We must start investigating sex offenders
성범죄자 수사 시작해야
who've committed a crime against minors.
미성년자를 대상으로 범죄를 저지른 사람.
My gosh.
이럴수가.
Chief Heo.
허 과장.
It can't happen, can it?
그런 일은 일어날 수 없어요, 그렇죠?
No, we can't do this.
아니요, 우리는 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
Our team has pride.
우리 팀에는 자부심이 있습니다.
How can I give them order with this report?
이 보고서를 통해 어떻게 그들에게 명령을 내릴 수 있습니까 ?
Gil-pyo.
길표.
Chief Heo. You have nothing to lose.
허 과장. 당신은 잃을 것이 없습니다.
At least try investigating.
적어도 조사해 보세요.
No, we can't do that.
아니요, 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
If we must investigate every single ex-con,
전과자 하나하나를 조사해야 한다면 ,
we'll need a lot of manpower too.
인력도 많이 필요할 거예요.
Don't you think so?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
Here's what I'm trying to say.
내가 말하려는 것은 이것이다.
I think it'll be impossible
불가능할 것 같아요
if we try to do this officially.
우리가 이것을 공식적으로 하려고 한다면요.
OFF THE RECORD
공표를 목적으로하지 않는
Just do it off the record.
그냥 녹음하지 말고 하세요.
Let's end the meeting.
회의를 마치겠습니다.
Captain Yoon.
윤대위.
This is the first and the last time.
이번이 처음이자 마지막입니다.
DATABASE OF CRIMINAL RECORDS
범죄 기록 데이터베이스
Let's give a chance to the Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀에 기회를 주자 .
If they help our investigation,
조사에 도움이 된다면
we won't lose anything either.
우리도 아무것도 잃지 않을 것입니다.
It's off the record, so you'll have to move quietly.
오프더레코드 이므로 조용히 이동하셔야 합니다.
I don't think this is the place.
내 생각엔 이곳이 장소가 아닌 것 같아.
There. "Behavioral Analysis Team."
거기. "행동분석팀."
-Hello. -These are the lists of…
-안녕하세요. -다음은 목록입니다…
-Let's do this. -Yes.
- 이렇게 해보자. -예.
Your ID number
귀하의 ID 번호
is 630303-1126850.
630303-1126850입니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
On May 20, where were you
5월 20일, 당신은 어디에 있었나요?
between 12 p.m. to 4 p.m.?
낮 12시부터 오후 4시 사이?
LIST OF SEX OFFENDERS
성범죄자 목록
-Who are you? -Please excuse us.
-누구세요? -죄송합니다.
It has been a while since I was released. And I don't mess with kids.
석방된 지 꽤 시간이 지났습니다. 그리고 나는 아이들을 함부로 대하지 않습니다.
Where were you between 12 p.m. and 4 p.m. on May 20?
5월 20일 오후 12시부터 오후 4시 사이에 어디에 계셨나요 ?
Ever since I was released, I've kept a low profile.
저는 석방된 이후로 겉모습을 드러내지 않았습니다.
I'm innocent.
난 결백 해.
-Thank you. -Wait for me!
-감사합니다. -날 기다려!
Do you want ice cream?
아이스크림 먹을래?
Come out, come out
나오세요, 나오세요
Wherever you are
당신이 어디에 있든
Come on, we have to hide!
어서, 우리는 숨어야 해요!
Come out, come out
나오세요, 나오세요
Wherever you are
당신이 어디에 있든
Where did things go wrong?
어디서 문제가 발생했나요?
There's nothing we can do
우리가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어
other than cross out the list.
목록을 지우는 것 외에는.
Don't beat yourself up so much.
너무 자책하지 마세요.
-Excuse me. -Yes, what is it?
-실례합니다. -네, 뭔데요?
Instead of searching the area with the list of sex offenders,
성범죄자 목록으로 지역을 검색하는 대신 ,
why don't we try to find a sex offender in the area who lives alone?
지역에서 혼자 사는 성범죄자를 찾아보는 건 어떨까요 ?
That'll take too long.
시간이 너무 오래 걸릴 거예요.
He has a point.
그는 일리가 있다.
If he recently moved to the area, we may not find him on our list.
만약 그가 최근에 그 지역으로 이사했다면 우리 목록에서 그를 찾지 못할 수도 있습니다.
Yes, I don't think it's a bad idea.
네, 나쁜 생각은 아닌 것 같아요.
let's find a list of men in their thirties and forties
30대와 40대 남성의 목록을 찾아보자
who live alone in the area.
그 지역에 혼자 사는 사람.
We started, so let's get it done no matter what.
우리는 시작했으니 무슨 일이 있어도 끝까지 해내자.
Yes, let's do it.
응, 해보자.
CHANGEUI-DONG OFFICE
창의동사무소
I'm Senior Officer Nam Il-young from Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
서울지방경찰청 남일영 형사입니다 .
Give me a list of men in their thirties and forties who live alone in this area.
이 지역에 혼자 사는 30~40대 남성의 목록을 알려주십시오 .
Everyone?
모두들?
Take a look at that one.
저거 좀 보세요.
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
You need to see this.
당신은 이것을 볼 필요가 있습니다.
These four weren't found
이 4개는 발견되지 않았습니다
on the criminal records database at the police agency.
경찰청 범죄기록 데이터베이스에
They declared their move later, so they weren't caught in the system.
나중에 이동을 선언했기 때문에 시스템에 잡히지 않았습니다.
So some were left out.
그래서 일부는 제외되었습니다.
Yes, we might end up catching the culprit easily.
네, 범인을 쉽게 잡을 수도 있어요 .
Captain Kook, we need to meet.
국 선장님, 만나야 해요.
The four of us will check out one address each.
우리 4명은 각각 주소 하나씩을 확인하겠습니다.
CRIMINAL HISTORY RECORD
범죄경력기록
Changeui-dong Youngshin Apartment…
창의동 영신아파트…
39-1 CHANGEUI-DONG
창의동 39-1
The items are somewhat neatly organized.
항목이 어느 정도 깔끔하게 정리되어 있습니다.
The house is close to the alley in Changeui-dong
집은 창의동 골목과 가깝습니다
where the body parts were first found.
신체 부위가 처음 발견된 곳
I think I found the place.
장소를 찾은 것 같아요.
Wait for me.
날 기다려.
This guy is the culprit.
이 사람이 범인입니다.
MISSING, LEE SOO-HYUN, AGE 5
실종 이수현, 5세
I'm sure Soo-hyun's fingers are around his house.
확실히 수현의 손가락은 집 주변에 있을 것입니다.
There are only eight.
8개밖에 없습니다.
We're missing two fingers of a girl!
우리는 여자의 손가락 두 개가 없어졌어요!
Please search thoroughly!
꼼꼼히 검색해주세요!
-Yes, ma'am.
-네 부인.
-Where are the two fingers… -That haven't turned up yet?
-두 손가락은 어디에… -아직 나오지 않았나요?
There are three fingerprints?
지문이 3개인가요?
It's strange that those were the only prints.
그게 유일한 지문이라는 것이 이상합니다 .
He either has an odd grip or is missing fingers.
그는 그립력이 이상하거나 손가락이 없습니다.
He disposed of the body parts at different times and locations.
그는 신체 부위를 다양한 시간과 장소에 폐기했습니다.
-Where could… -Cho Hyun-gil be hiding?
-어디에… -조현길이 숨어있을까?